<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>REPL adventures</title>
  <link href="https://blog.ebbinghaus.me/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="https://blog.ebbinghaus.me/"/>
  <updated>2022-02-17T14:32:56.463016Z</updated>
  <id>https://blog.ebbinghaus.me/</id>
  <author>
    <name>Björn Ebbinghaus</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <id>https://blog.ebbinghaus.me/my-first-post.html</id>
    <link href="https://blog.ebbinghaus.me/my-first-post.html"/>
    <title>My first post!</title>
    <published>2021-12-06T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2021-12-06T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p>This is my first post. Hopefully one of many to come!</p>
]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://blog.ebbinghaus.me/decide-comma20-demo.html</id>
    <link href="https://blog.ebbinghaus.me/decide-comma20-demo.html"/>
    <title>decide: Supporting Participatory Budgeting with Online Argumentation</title>
    <category term="decision-making" label="decision-making"/>
    <category term="participatory budgeting" label="participatory budgeting"/>
    <category term="online-argumentation" label="online-argumentation"/>
    <category term="demo" label="demo"/>
    <published>2020-09-01T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2020-09-01T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p><strong>Authors</strong>: <a class="author" href="mailto:ebbinghaus@hhu.de">Björn Ebbinghaus</a>, Martin Mauve</p><p><a href='https://wwwcn.cs.uni-duesseldorf.de/publications/publications/library/Ebbinghaus2020a.pdf'>PDF</a></p><p><div class="aspect-w-16 aspect-h-9"> <iframe src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/Owexcgd5pOU" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen></iframe> </div></p><h2>Introduction</h2><p>With <i>decide</i> we want to enable a large crowd of participants to decide on a complex issue, such as how to make the best use of a given budget. In particular, we are interested in understanding how online argumentation and online prioritization schemes can be combined to support collective decision-making.</p><p>We have used decide to let our students collectively decide on how to use a real-world budget to improve the computer science course of study at HHU<!&ndash;\cite{Ebbinghaus2019a}&ndash;>. In our demo we will show the setup used in that experiment and report on the outcome.</p><h2>The <i>decide</i> collective decision system</h2><p><i>decide</i> employs a three-step approach to collective decision-making. In the first step participants can introduce proposals. For each proposal an estimated cost is provided by that participant. All participants then use dialog-based argumentation<!&ndash;\cite{Krauthoff2018b}&ndash;> to argue about the validity and priority of the proposals. <!&ndash;This is shown in \autoref{fig:dbas-decide}.&ndash;></p><p>In the second step the proposals are validated. That is to say in our specific experiment we checked if there are any reasons why any of the proposals cannot be realized even if the proposed resources were allocated to it. For example, one proposal required significant construction work which was not feasible. The remaining proposals with the attached argumentation then enter the next step.</p><p>In the final step the participants prioritize the proposals. First, the participants select the proposals that they want to support. Then they order the supported proposals by their own priority <!&ndash;(see \autoref{fig:decide-example})&ndash;>. The arguments attached to the proposals can be viewed and extended in this phase, but no new proposals can be created. The final result is then calculated using a truncated Borda count followed by a greedy collection of proposals which fit the budget.</p><h2>Future Work</h2><p>We have received valuable feedback from the students who used <i>decide</i>. One main issue is that dialog-based argumentation tends to involve the participant in a lengthy exchange of pro and contra arguments. This is good to gain an in-depth understanding of all positions, but it makes it hard to gain a quick overview of the main points. One main issue is therefore to improve the argumentation step and also to test other approaches &ndash;– such as nested pro and contra lists.</p><p>A second issue is the algorithm used to reach a decision. We would like to experiment with other voting schemes and see which of those are considered to be fair by the participants.</p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://blog.ebbinghaus.me/biosphere.html</id>
    <link href="https://blog.ebbinghaus.me/biosphere.html"/>
    <title>Biosphere</title>
    <category term="clojure" label="clojure"/>
    <category term="virtual-life" label="virtual-life"/>
    <published>2020-02-29T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2020-02-29T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <content type="html"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://blog.ebbinghaus.me/jebediah-arguing-with-a-social-bot.html</id>
    <link href="https://blog.ebbinghaus.me/jebediah-arguing-with-a-social-bot.html"/>
    <title>Jebediah – Arguing With a Social Bot</title>
    <category term="dialog-game execution platform" label="dialog-game execution platform"/>
    <category term="online-argumentation" label="online-argumentation"/>
    <category term="conversational ui" label="conversational ui"/>
    <category term="demo" label="demo"/>
    <category term="AI" label="AI"/>
    <published>2018-09-01T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2018-09-01T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p><strong>Authors</strong>: Christian Meter, <a class="author" href="mailto:ebbinghaus@hhu.de">Björn Ebbinghaus</a>, Martin Mauve</p><p><a href='https://wwwcn.cs.uni-duesseldorf.de/publications/publications/library/Meter2018a.pdf'>PDF</a></p><h2>Introduction</h2><p>In prior work we introduced the <a href='https://dbas.cs.uni-duesseldorf.de'><i>Dialog-Based Argumentation System</i> (D-BAS)</a> [1], a <i>Dialog Game Execution Platform</i> (DGEP) [2] for dialog-based online argumentation. D-BAS allows users to exchange proposals and arguments with each other in the form of a time-shifted dialog where arguments are presented and acted upon one-at-a-time. It is designed as a full-stack, stand alone web-application.</p><p>However, currently, the vast majority of online discussions takes place in social networks such as Facebook or Twitter and not on dedicated argumentation web-sites.  We therefore investigated how the functionality of a dialog-game execution platform, such as D-BAS, can be included in a seamless way into social networks. Our solution to the problem is a social bot called Jebediah. It provides a front-end to DGEPs that can be integrated into social networks in a seamless way.</p><h2><i>Jebediah</i> – a social bot for online argumentation</h2><p><figure>     <img src="assets/jeb.png" alt="Dialog between a user and the conversation agent.">     <figcaption><b>Figure 1.</b> Conversation with Jebediah. On the right side is the user's           input. On the left side are the answers.     </figcaption> </figure></p><p><i>Jebediah</i> is a social bot based on Google’s framework <a href='https://dialogflow.com'>Dialogflow</a> for <i>Artificial Intelligence</i> (AI) development. It connects Dialogflow with a DGEP such as D-BAS’ backend. Dialogflow enables a seamless integration into many popular social networks, e.g. Facebook or Twitter, and provides  processing of text-input from conversations. We leverage this to enable natural language access where the AI is used to parse and interpret the user’s input, whereas the interpreted data is sent to D-BAS’ DGEP, in order to calculate the next steps in the discussion. This setup allows us to directly have a conversation with interested users without the need to leave the current site and to provide a solution to reduce crowded comment sections, e.g. inside a Facebook post.</p><p>Jebediah exposes the full functionality of D-BAS, i.e. collect statements from users, integrate them into a discussion graph and present the next statement to the user (see Fig. 1). It is then possible, in natural language, to interact with arguments and experiences from those users. Users can also start a dialog with the agent and ask for possible entities in the discussion, e.g. topics or other positions.</p><p>Where D-BAS’ interface shows the user a list of possible steps to choose from, this is hardly manageable in a text-only or even voice-only environment. Therefore Jebediah has to lead the user in a way that advances the conversation into deeper levels of the topic, while being flexible enough to react to user actions which are not a usual part of the D-BAS discussion flow. This is even more important in a voice interface where the user has to memorize the current part of the discussion.</p><h2>Related Work</h2><p>Arvina [3] is a system that bears a lot of similarities to our work. With Arvina it is possible to replay previously stored discussions and interact with the recording. Multiple real users can participate in the debate and also add new statements. Jebediah, in contrast, aims at enabling a seamless integration of a DGEP into social networks and at providing a discussion using natural language.</p><h2>References</h2><ul><li>[1] T. Krauthoff, C. Meter, G. Betz, M. Baurmann, and M. Mauve, “D-BAS – A Dialog-Based Online Argumentation System,” in Computational Models of Argument, September 2018, pp. 325–336.</li><li>[2] F. Bex, J. Lawrence, and C. Reed, “Generalising argument dialogue with the dialogue game executionplatform.” in COMMA, 2014, pp. 141–152.</li><li>[3] M. Snaith, J. Lawrence, and C. Reed, “Mixed initiative argument in public deliberation,” Online Deliberation, 2010.</li></ul>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://blog.ebbinghaus.me/talk-core-async.html</id>
    <link href="https://blog.ebbinghaus.me/talk-core-async.html"/>
    <title>Talk about clojure.core.async</title>
    <summary>I did a talk about core.async for the 'Clojure Meetup Düsseldorf'.</summary>
    <category term="clojure" label="clojure"/>
    <category term="talk" label="talk"/>
    <published>2018-01-24T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2018-01-24T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p>As a programmer who tries to use <a href="https://clojure.org/" rel="nofollow">Clojure</a><a href="https://clojurescript.org/" rel="nofollow">(Script)</a> wherever possible, I am a frequent visitor of the <a href="https://www.meetup.com/de-DE/Dusseldorf-Clojure-Meetup" rel="nofollow">Clojure Meetup Düsseldorf</a>.
Recently I was asked what clojure tools/libraries I am using, worth sharing. It happens that a couple of days before, I came in contact with <a href="https://github.com/clojure/core.async">core.async</a> while writing a single page application in clojurescript.
One thing led to another, and I agreed to talk about <a href="https://github.com/clojure/core.async">core.async</a> at the next meetup.</p>
<p>As a novice in <a href="https://github.com/clojure/core.async">core.async</a> myself, this was an interesting task ahead.
Having to read a paper about <a href="https://dl.acm.org/citation.cfm?id=502057" rel="nofollow">staged event driven architecture</a> for the lecture <em>Architecture of Distributed Systems</em> introduced me to the advantages of separate running threads and the communication between via queues/channels between them.</p>
<p>After the talk we played around a little with a playground I developed, to test <a href="https://github.com/clojure/core.async">core.async</a> in a scenario of an ant colony.
This playground has the goal to make everything asynchronous, which maybe wasn't an ideal use of async, but it was fun at least to watch the little ants run around.
The code can be found on <a href="https://github.com/clojuredus/async-ants">GitHub</a>.</p>
<p>All in all it was a nice evening, and I hope the listeners have learned something they can use to build great software. If I'm stumbling over something in the future I will definitely consider sharing it on a meetup again.</p>
<p>Thanks to <a href="https://www.invision.de/" rel="nofollow">InVision</a>, which hosted the event and provided us with drinks and <a href="https://www.instagram.com/invision_chefs/" rel="nofollow">great food</a>.
Also check out <a href="https://joyheron.com" rel="nofollow">Joy Heron</a>s wonderful <a href="https://joyheron.com/sketchnote/clojure-meetup/2018/01/24/clojure-meetup.html" rel="nofollow">sketchnote</a>!</p>
<p>The keynote can be found <a href="https://www.icloud.com/keynote/0UasaP9fgxNOu-bwgxZMhH5Tg" rel="nofollow">here</a>.</p>
]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
</feed>
